<resources>
    <string name="app_name">WeatherApp</string>
    <string name="rare_facts"><![CDATA[Cold Weather Can Boost Brain Function\n\nExposure to cold weather can improve cognitive function, as the body works harder to maintain core temperature, leading to increased alertness and focus. Studies suggest that people tend to think more clearly in cooler environments compared to very hot conditions.\n\nRain and Arthritis Pain\n\nThere\'s a common belief that rainy weather worsens joint pain, but science hasn’t conclusively proven a direct link. However, changes in barometric pressure (which often occurs before rain) may cause joints to expand slightly, which could trigger pain in people with arthritis.\n\nSunlight and Immune System\n\nModerate sun exposure boosts vitamin D production, which is essential for immune function. Vitamin D helps the body fight off pathogens and may reduce the risk of autoimmune diseases. However, too much UV exposure can suppress the immune system, so balance is key.\n\nThunderstorms Can Trigger Asthma\n\nThunderstorms can cause a spike in asthma attacks due to a phenomenon called \"thunderstorm asthma.\" During a storm, pollen grains and mold spores are broken into smaller fragments by rain and wind, making them easier to inhale and triggering asthma in sensitive individuals.\n\nHumidity and Dehydration\n\nIn humid weather, the body\'s ability to cool itself by sweating is reduced. Because sweat doesn\'t evaporate as efficiently in high humidity, the body continues to produce more sweat, increasing the risk of dehydration without you realizing it.\n\nDry Air and Skin\n\nCold, dry weather causes moisture loss from the skin, leading to dry, flaky skin and exacerbating conditions like eczema. It\'s not just winter, though—air conditioning in the summer can also dry out your skin, so moisturizing year-round is important.\n\nBarometric Pressure and Migraines\n\nChanges in barometric pressure, especially a rapid drop, can trigger migraines. People who are sensitive to pressure changes may experience headaches even before a storm or drastic weather shift happens.\n\nHot Weather and Mood Swings\n\nHigher temperatures can increase aggression and irritability in some individuals. Studies have shown a correlation between extremely hot weather and spikes in crime rates, possibly due to discomfort, dehydration, or the body\'s struggle to regulate heat.\n\nWind and Mental Health\n\nSome studies suggest that strong, persistent winds (like those in windy regions) can negatively affect mood, leading to feelings of anxiety or depression. In particular, the dry, warm wind known as the Foehn wind has been linked to mood disturbances.\n\nWeather and Heart Attacks\n\nCold weather puts extra strain on the cardiovascular system, increasing the risk of heart attacks. When it\'s cold, blood vessels constrict, and blood pressure rises, making it harder for the heart to pump blood efficiently. Sudden exertion in cold weather can increase heart attack risk, especially in people with pre-existing conditions.\n\nSunlight boosts mood\n\nExposure to natural sunlight increases serotonin levels, which helps improve your mood and energy levels. Just 15 minutes of sunlight can make a difference!\n   \nCold weather burns calories\n\nShivering in cold temperatures forces your body to work harder to stay warm, which can burn extra calories.\n\nHumidity helps skin\n\nA bit of humidity in the air keeps your skin hydrated, reducing dryness and irritation. But be cautious not to over-hydrate in extremely humid conditions!\n\nWind can dehydrate you\n\nWindy conditions can speed up water loss from your skin, so staying hydrated is key when it\'s breezy.\n\nClouds don’t block UV rays\n\nEven on cloudy days, up to 80% of UV rays can penetrate the clouds, so sunscreen is still essential.\n\nRain improves air quality\n\nRain washes away dust, pollen, and pollutants from the air, making it easier to breathe and reducing allergy symptoms.\n\nSnow glare can damage eyes\n\nSnow reflects up to 80% of sunlight, increasing the risk of UV exposure to your eyes. Wearing sunglasses in the snow can protect against damage.\n\nBarometric pressure affects joints\n\nDrops in atmospheric pressure before a storm can cause joint pain to flare up. Stretching and staying active can help reduce discomfort.\n \nThunderstorms trigger asthma\n\nThe strong winds and humidity from thunderstorms can stir up pollen and mold, which may trigger asthma attacks or allergies.\n\nCold showers strengthen immunity\n\nAfter being exposed to cold weather, taking a brief cold shower can improve circulation and boost your immune system!\n\nWhen to use Lip Balm\n\nBelow 50°F (10°C): Cold air is often drier and can cause your lips to lose moisture quickly, leading to chapped lips. Lip balm is essential in these conditions. Dry Heat (>85°F / 29°C): In hot, dry environments, like deserts, lips can also dry out. Using a lip balm with SPF protection helps keep them moisturized and shielded from the sun.\n\nAbove 2,000 feet (600 meters): The air becomes thinner and drier at higher elevations, increasing the risk of dry, chapped lips. Lip balm with SPF is particularly important here due to increased UV exposure. Above 5,000 feet (1,500 meters): At this point, UV exposure can be 20% stronger than at sea level, and the dryness of the air intensifies. Frequent use of lip balm is advised.\n]]></string>
    <string name="error_loading_temperatures">Error loading temperatures</string>
    <string name="hypthermia_1">Hypothermia: Typically occurs when the body temperature drops below 95°F (35°C). Risk increases in temperatures below 50°F (10°C) with wind chill.</string>
    <string name="respiratory_1">Respiratory Issues: Cold air can affect individuals with asthma or COPD, often when temperatures drop below 50°F (10°C).</string>
    <string name="frostbite_1">Frostbite: Can occur in temperatures below 32°F (0°C), especially with wind chill. Risk increases significantly in subzero temperatures.</string>
    <string name="heartattack_1">Increased Heart Attack Risk: Increased risk can occur in temperatures below 32°F (0°C), especially for those with existing heart conditions.</string>
    <string name="heat_exhaust_1">Heat Exhaustion: Usually occurs in temperatures above 80°F (27°C), especially with high humidity and prolonged physical activity.</string>
    <string name="dehydration_1">Dehydration: Risk increases in temperatures above 80°F (27°C), especially during exercise or outdoor activities.</string>
    <string name="heat_stroke_1">Heat Stroke: Can occur at temperatures above 104°F (40°C), particularly when coupled with exertion and dehydration.</string>
    <string name="skin_issues_1">Skin Issues (Sunburn): Can happen when UV index levels are high, which can occur at various temperatures, often when it’s sunny and above 70°F (21°C).</string>
    <string name="allergies_1">Allergies: Pollen counts can rise with temperatures as low as 60°F (15°C), depending on the plant species.</string>
    <string name="humidity_1"><![CDATA[Humidity < 30%: Leads to respiratory irritation, dry skin, increased infection risk, static electricity discomfort.]]></string>
    <string name="humidity_2"><![CDATA[Humidity > 50%: Risk of mold and dust mite growth increases, increased sweat and discomfort begins.]]></string>
    <string name="humidity_3"><![CDATA[Humidity > 60%: Significant increase in mold, mildew, and dust mites; respiratory conditions may worsen.]]></string>
    <string name="humidity_4"><![CDATA[Humidity > 70%: Heat-related illnesses, severe discomfort, and heightened allergy or asthma problems and possible joint pains.]]></string>
    <string name="low_air_pressure_1">Low Air Pressure (less than 980 hPa) threshold can vary by city but is associated with migraines, joint pain, respiratory issues (shortness of breath and asthma), sinus discomfort, altitude sickness and mood disturbances</string>
    <string name="high_air_pressure_1">High air pressure (more than 1050 hPa) threshold can cause health concerns including, barometric pressure headaches, sinus pressure and congestion, joint pain relief, and blood pressure and circulatory concerns.</string>
    <string name="temperature">%1$s °C</string>
    <string name="humidity">%1$s% Humidity</string>
    <string name="air_pressure">%1$s hPa</string>
    <string name="na">N/A</string>
    <string name="temp_c_semantics">Temperature in degrees Celsius is %1$s</string>
    <string name="temp_c">%1$s°C</string>
    <string name="weather_icon_semantic">Weather icon representing weather</string>
    <string name="failure_message">Failed to get data for:</string>
    <string name="failed_to_load">Failed to load weather data.</string>
    <string name="no_internet_message">No Internet Connection</string>
    <string name="failed_from_no_internet">Failed from no internet connection.</string>
    <string name="loading">Loading…</string>
    <string name="loading_weather_data">Loading weather data</string>
    <string name="press_search_weather">Press Search Weather</string>
    <string name="no_weather_data_available">No weather data available</string>
    <string name="temperature_zoom">Temperature Zoom</string>
    <string name="navigate_to_temperature_zoom_screen">Navigate to temperature zoom screen</string>
    <string name="search_city_weather">Search City Weather</string>
    <string name="search_weather_for_the_entered_city">Search weather for the entered city</string>
    <string name="get_your_local_weather">Get Your Local Weather</string>
    <string name="search_weather_for_local_weather_by_geo_coords">Search weather for local Weather by Geo-coords</string>
    <string name="location_permission_needed">Location Permission Needed</string>
    <string name="this_app_needs_the_location_permission_to_fetch_weather_data_for_your_current_location">This app needs the location permission to fetch weather data for your current location.</string>
    <string name="grant">Grant</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="weatherappprefs">WeatherAppPrefs</string>
    <string name="tokyo">Tokyo</string>
    <string name="city_name">CITY_NAME</string>
    <string name="temperature_c">Temperature: %1$s°C</string>
    <string name="https_openweathermap_org_img_wn_2x_png">https://openweathermap.org/img/wn/%1$s@2x.png</string>
    <string name="current_temperature_in_degrees_celsius_is_c">Current temperature in degrees Celsius is %1$s°C</string>
</resources>